Guide to the Frederic Spiegelberg Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Frederic Spiegelberg papers
1916-1994
1936-1994
SC0631
Spiegelberg, Frederic, b. 1897
20.5 Linear feet (16 boxes)
Collection includes correspondence, lecture notes, course materials, manuscripts, publications, photographs, newsletters, and other materials. Some of the correspondence and publications are in German.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was given to the Stanford University Archives by the estate of Frederick Spiegelberg in 1995. Addional materials in accession 2011-184 were received from the California Institute of Integral Studies in August 2011.
Information about Access
Access: Materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Spiegelberg taught religious studies and other courses in Asian studies at Stanford from 1941 until his retirement in 1960. He was voted a "great teacher" by the Student Executive Committee in 1950. Born in Germany, he obtained his doctorate at Tubingen in 1922 and a theological degree from the German Lutheran Church in 1925; in 1937 he escaped Nazi Germany with the help of Paul Tillich. Spiegelberg helped found the American Academy of Asian Studies in San Francisco in 1950 and became its director in 1951.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes correspondence, lecture notes, course materials, manuscripts, publications, photographs, newsletters, and other materials. Some of the correspondence and publications are in German. Correspondents include Aurobindo Ghose, Amiya Chakravarty, Paul Du Breuil, Frederick Franck, Raoul J. Fajardo, C. G. Jung, John Levy, Rollo May, Nyogen Senzaki, Swami Sivananda, Paul and Hanna Tillich, and Alan Watts.
Access Terms
California Institute of Asian Studies.; Chakravarty, Amiya Chandra; Du Breuil, Paul; Fajardo, Raoul J.; Franck, Frederick, 1909-2006; Ghose, Aurobindo, 1872-1950; Jung, C. G. (Carl Gustav), 1875-1961; Levy, John; May, Rollo; Pacific Coast Theology Group.; Senzaki, Nyogen; Sivananda, Swami; Spiegelberg, Frederic, b. 1897; Tillich, Hanna; Tillich, Paul, 1886-1965; Watts, Alan, 1915-1973; Religion--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Professional Papers, 1927-1994; Series 1
    - Address Book (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Academy of Asian Studies – course list, 1951-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Oriental Society, 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anand, Mulk Raj, articles (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Andersen, Per, letter and article, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Appointment letters, 1927-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Arthur, Gavin, horoscope for FS with letter, 1948, and astrological chart for Mrs. Spiegelberg (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Arthur, Gavin: correspondence, publications, photograph, and clippings, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Association for Transpersonal Psychology, conference booklets and correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Aurobindo - FS’s paper and related correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Aurobindo - photographs, 1951 and undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Auroville, the City of Dawn: brochure, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Baha'I faith, articles on, 1931-1953 and undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bass, Eric: notice and clipping of art exhibition and photograph, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bernard, Ruth, letter, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bible of the World (edited by Robert O. Ballou in collaboration with FS): brochures and reviews, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Boeke, Rudolph: Levensteken [newsletter], 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Book of Equanimity (chapters, author not given) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bubba Free John: publications, letter by Crane Montano about new work by Bubba (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Buddhist ephemera: The Buddhist Service (World Congress of Faiths, 1936) and Indian postcards depicting elements of the Buddha's life (1937 artwork) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Buddhist images, text, no author stated, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - California Institute of Asian Studies, accreditation 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - California Institute of Asian Studies, correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - California Institute of Asian Studies, course and class announcements (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - California Institute of Asian Studies, Faculty Handbook, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - California Institute of Asian Studies, FS comments on committee report (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - California Institute of Asian Studies, FS on purpose and future (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - California Institute of Asian Studies, grant of FS's books, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - California Institute of Asian Studies, minutes, agenda, etc., 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - California Institute of Asian Studies, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - California Institute of Transpersonal Psychology, correspondence and other materials, 1975-1876 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Campbell, Ronald L., reserach proposal with letter to FS, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Ceremony of the Vajra Crown, S.F., program and clipping, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Chakravarty, Amiya, correspondence and announcements, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Comments on FS's Living Religions of the World (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Conference and meeting materials (assorted) 1947-1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, A-B (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, C-D (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, E-F (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, G-J (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, K-M (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, N-P (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, R-S (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, T-Z (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1972-78 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - unidentified, fragments, etc. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re possible visit to India, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence [FS was in England part of this year] 1937 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, outgoing (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence - postcards (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - postcards (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - postcards (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - postcards (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Coward, Harold - articles (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Cultural Integration Fellowship, correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - d'Orge, Jeanne – poem with note, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Dahl, Arthur, correspondence, 1960-1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Dance, Indian (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Date book, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Date books, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Date books, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Date books, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Date books, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Date books, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Davis, Virginia, typescript poems 1978 (photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Dream (Traum) - 2 pages in German, author not noted (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - du Breuil, Paul: correspondence, photos, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - du Maurier, Gwendolen: letter to Spiegelberg (mentions Tillich), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Durckheim, Karlfried, correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - England, World Congress of Faith and Baha'I Summer School, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Eranos, conferences, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Erhard, Werner, correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Ernst, Max, obituary (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Esalen Institute (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - European addresses and miscellany (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Fajardo, Raoul J., letter 1983 and printed poem and music 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Florian, Dorothea, correspondence, 1978-1987 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Foster, Durwood, "On Tillich's Idea of a Theology of Culture," 1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - “Foundations and Frontiers," course bulletin for UC Extension, Santa Cruz, summer 1980 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Franck, Frederick, correspondence and other items 1975-1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Graduate Theological Union, information statements and one letter, 1968, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Grunwedel, Alfr., “Die Geschichten der 84 Zauberer (Mahashiddhas) aus dem Tibetischen Ubersetzt” 1916 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Hartog Agencies, correspondence and contract, 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - “Heimstatte fur Tibeter in der Schweiz” [Home for Tibetans in Switzerland]- no author stated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Henderson, K.D.D. “U.S.G.R. Newsletter” 1966 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Hillman, James, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Humboldt-Gesellschaft, correspondence and other materials, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Hunger Project and Werner Erhard, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Images (Buddhist) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Indian philosophy, assorted texts (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Insel Verlag, contract and correspondence re translation and publication of his book The Living World Religions, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Institute of Mentalphysics: booklet and other materials, 1937 and undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Jung, C. G. – correspondence, 1936-1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Jung, C. G. – interview Nov. 9, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Jung, C. G. – miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Jung on Tibetan block prints (translated into English), 1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Jung Foundation for Analytical Psychology, catalog and brochures, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Jung Institute of Los Angeles, program announcement, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Jung Institute of San Francisco, minutes, correspondence, etc., 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Jung Institute of San Francisco, programs 1969-1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Jung Institute (Zurich), correspondence and notes, 1957-1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Jung Institute (Zurich), programs, 1965-1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Keller, Jules, correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Kochling, “Psychotherapie mit Jungen Suchmittelabhangigen” undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Lantzsch, Gottfried Helllmut, correspondence (in German), 1963 and n.d. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Lauf, Detlef Ingo, correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Lessing, Mrs. Ferdinand, correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Levy, Adele and John, letters, 1983-1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Levy, Adele and John, letters, date imcomplete (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Levy, John - note and xerox of article, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Li, Juan, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Lysne, Robin H., poetry (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Ma, Ananada Mayi, biography (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Magnolia Melodies – lyrics to Stanford songs (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Mann Ranch Seminars, correspondence and brochures, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - May, Rollo, correspondence, ca. 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - McGaughey, Douglas, chapter 13 “From Vulgar to Refined Skepticism: Faith in a Post-Metaphysical Context,” undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous materials (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Mukunda Das (Michael Makowsky), correspondence and class proposal, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Mullenburg, James, “The Biblical Background for a Theology of the Laity,” undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Nakamura, Hajime “Tibetan Studies in Japan,” undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Oertly, Anna, correspondence, 1968-1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Osbelt, Ulrich, letter, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Pacific Coast Theology Group: membership lists, meeting announcements, and papers (several on Paul Tillich’s work), 1957-1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Pantheon books, correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Prentice-Hall, correspondence (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Proteus Institute, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Rahind (??), R.N., letters (one mentions the Tripitaka given to Stanford), 1950 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Reiman, Maria, "Die Entwicklung des Denkens," with letter, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Reps, Paul, letter, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Ross, Nancy W., letter, 1971, and article, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Roy, Dilip Kumar, letter and brochure re class, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Roy, Shambhu Nath, correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - San Francisco Art Institute, notes, correspondence, programs re guest lecture by FS, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Sankara’s Commentary to the Vedanta-Sutras [mimeographed pages with notes] (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Schaeffer, Rudolph, holiday card with note, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Senzaki, Nyogen, talks to SU classes, 1952-1953, and letter 1953 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Singh, Lalan Prasad, correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Sivananda, correspondence, 1952-1959 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Smith, Huston, clippings and miscellany (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Spiegelberg, book announcements (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Spiegelberg, c.v. and biographical materials (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Spiegelberg, lecture brochure (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Spiegelberg, list of art works (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Srivastava, R. S., letters, 1965, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Stanford Research Institute – Yoga research, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Stanford - Sloan Program, 1964-1972 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Stanford University ID and business card (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Stanford University appointment letters, 1941-1961 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Stanford University, administrative correspondence, 1944, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Stanford University Dept. of Religious Studies newsletter, 1975, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Stanford University, gift of Tibetan Tripitaka, clipping, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Starr King School for the Ministry, correspondence and program material, 1955-1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Starr King School for the Ministry, correspondence and notes, 1955-1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Staude, John-Raphael, c. v. and publication announcement, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Stauffacher, Jack – holiday card (poem and image, circa 1964) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Suksma (subtle body) – references to (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Swartley, William, “The Analytical Psychologist and the Guru,” undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Symposium at San Jose State, “Approaches to the Self,” correspondence, program materials, and notes, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Tibet, articles, clippings, etc, 1950-1954 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Tibetan art work (2 pieces) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Tibetan artifacts, correspondence and misc. note (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Tibetan artifacts, photographs (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Tibetan Buddhism: outline in Tibetan script, transliteration, and English (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Tibetan ghost traps, articles and illustrations (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Tibetan mandalas, examples of (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Tibetan refugess in Europe and US: clippings and letter from Marguarite Reinhard of the Swiss Red Cross and Jigdal Sakyapa of Seattle, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Tibetan teachers and center (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Tillich, Hanna, poetry and prose [in German] (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Tillich, Paul and Hanna, correspondence, 1937-1959 and undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Tillich, Paul, "Die politisches und geistige Aufgabe der deutschen Emigration," 1938 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Tillich, Paul, "Man and Society in Religious Socialism," paper presented at the National Council on Religion in Higher Education, Sept. 1943 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Tillich, Paul, "Meinen deutschen Freunden; Das deutsche Original der Einfuhrung in mein englisches Buch "The Interpretation of History." 20 August 1936. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Tillich, Paul, "Systematic Theology" [mimeographed text], 1945 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Tillich, Paul, "The Theological Method" [mimeographed text], undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Tillich, Paul - sermon, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Tillich, Paul, Santa Barbara seminar 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Tillich, Paul, interview with Heidegger as related to Spiegelberg in 1963 (in German) (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Tillich, Paul, miscellany (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Travel and hotel correspondence, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Trip to India, 1949 – correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Trip to India, 1949 – financial and miscellaneous records (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Trip to India, 1949 – travel arrangements (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Trip to India, 1949 – photographs (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Trips (Europe, Stanford Sierra Camp) 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Tyberg, Judith, "Sanskrit Keys to India's Wisdom" [mimeographed thesis] (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - University of Ranchi (India), correspondence re Ph.D. theses, 1967-1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - University of San Francisco, correspondence and clipping re FS gift of Tibetan ghost trap, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - The Vairagya-Satakan or the Hundred Verses on Renunciation by Bhartrihari – typescript [a classical text?] (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Varda, Jean, clippings, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Watts, Alan, correspondence, 1945-1983 [2 letters from Watts, 1945 and undated, and one postcard, 1963; one letter from Monica Furlong re Watts, 1983] (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Watts, Alan: Alan Watts Journal, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Watts, Alan: publications and articles (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Yandell, James, “The Imitation of Jung--An Exploration of the Meaning of ‘Jungian’”, conference paper, March 1977 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Yoga, miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Zen and possibly other Eastern issues (German text on), no author stated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Zimmer, Heinrich “Maya, der indische Mythos” (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Class Materials, 1927-1978; Series 2
    - Approaches to Asia (C.I.A.S.) colloquium: notices, cyllabi, correspondence, clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Approaches to Asia (C.I.A.S.) colloquium: FS notes, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - ARAS (Archive for Research in Archetypal Symbolism) - course proposal with correspondence, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Buddhism (SU E162), class syllabi, tests, etc., 1945-1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Class materials (SU and other), 1955-1961 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Class materials: handwritten lecture/topic schedules, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Collection and study of popular color prints from India (SU proposal), 1957 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Comparative Theology (mostly source materials), Fall 1958 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - India Studies, essential readings (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Indian philosophy – class sources, materials, notes, 1945-1976 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Mimeographed handouts (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Paratheology: course materials, notes, and other items, 1964-1977 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Paratheology, notes and sources # 1 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Paratheology, notes and sources # 2 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Paratheology, notes and sources # 3 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Paratheology, notes and sources # 4 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Paratheology, images (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Paratheology, miscellaneous sources (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Psychological claification of Sanskrit terms - workshop, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Psychology of meditation - outline (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Tibetan Society and Culture (Research Seminar on), University of Washington, Seattle, Summer 1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Technische Hochschule [Technical College] Dresden, class lists from classes taught by FS, 1927-1937 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Lectures, 1929-1977; Series 3
    - Lecture announcements (mostly East Coast), 1938-1942 and n.d. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lectures 1956-1958, announcements and clippings (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Lectures 1956-58, correspondence (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Lectures 1956-58, notes and outlines (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Lectures: correspondence, notes, flyers, etc., 1955-1959 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Class and lecture announcements, 1969, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Lecture on art (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Lecture notes: Asiatic Art as a way of self-realization (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Lecture notes: Is Asia ripe for peace, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Lecture notes: The idea of personal devotion in Bhagavad Gita, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Lecture notes: The value of comparative religion / St. John of the Cross (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Notes on religious basis for Eastern art (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Lecture notes: Future of religion / traces of God / Joyce's Ulysses (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Lecture notes: How much can we know, Bryn Mawr, ca. 1938 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Lecture notes: on India [in German] (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Lecture notes: Indian Philosophy, The Panini-Darsana (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Lecture notes: Karl Barth, 1938-1943 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Lecture notes: Martin (?) lecture, includes notes on back of letter from Robert D. Ballou, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Notes on Religion in the atomic era, 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Lecture notes for Sanskrit class, Apr. 1956 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Notes on etymology of "to be" in Sanskrit (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Notes for a sermon (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Notes for sermon at Stanford, Aug. 3, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Lecture notes: spiritual autobiography, Nov. 9, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Lecture notes: description of Tada slides #1 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Lecture notes: description of Tada slides #2 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Tada photos [Tibet], 1929 and no date (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Notes on Tibet (talk at De Young Museum?), 1971 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Lecture notes: unicorns / palmistry / Kabbalah (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Lecture notes: Unitarian Church event, Palo Alto, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Lecture notes, What is man?, San Jose 1946 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Lecture notes in German 1937 and undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Lectures notes/address book, 1950s (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Lecture outlines (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Lecture notes, miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Notes and Notebooks, 1917-1980; Series 4
    - Notebook: Astrology, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Notebook: Children and religion 1946 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Notebook: Inner meaning of Christian dogma, notes for lecture series, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Notebook: Grace and mercy / symbolism of the mass / rebirth, reincarnation, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Notes: History of religion [or possibly Catholicism?] (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Notebook: Indian Dreams, 6 lectures about the history of religions given to the Analytical Psychology Club, New York, Jan.-March 1938 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Notes: memorial address for Mrs. Oscar Meyer (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Notebook: Philosophical problems in the interpretation of Indian and Chinese religious texts, 1938 and undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Notebook: notes from lectures on Plato and Islam (in German), 1917/18 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Notebook: Plotin (Plotinus), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Notebook: Ruysbroeck's "Spiritual Marriage" and other topics, 1941-42 and undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Notebook: Sanskrit, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Notebook: Steiner and Loyola (and other topics: Krishnamurti and Baha'I), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Notebook: Symbolism of the Mass, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Notebook: Yoga (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Notes: Alchemy and Yoga (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Notes: Yoga and Jung, 1974-80 (includes photo (Spiegelberg?) in notebook (Box 11, Folder 21)